<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab Blog on The Niederhuth Lab</title>
    <link>https://niederhuth.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab Blog on The Niederhuth Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 21:41:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://niederhuth.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Epigenomics?</title>
      <link>https://niederhuth.github.io/blog/what_is_epigenomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 13:54:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niederhuth.github.io/blog/what_is_epigenomics/</guid>
      <description>Epigenomics is different than epigenetics and it’s not simply a matter of scale. As I explained in my previous post, epigenetics, like genetics, is concerned with matters of inheritance. In contrast, epigenomics is the study of those factors that form chromatin, regardless of whether they are inherited. Chromatin roughly refers to those factors that interact with DNA and determine how it is “packaged” into its overall structure and it includes things like DNA methylation, histones, histone modifications, and non-coding RNAs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Epigenetics?</title>
      <link>https://niederhuth.github.io/blog/what_is_epigenetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:38:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niederhuth.github.io/blog/what_is_epigenetics/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetics is confusing. It’s one of those scientific concepts, like quantum mechanics or &amp;ldquo;survival of the fittest&amp;rdquo;, that are often misunderstood and misapplied. How widespread this confusion is, is made evident by the publication of entire papers dedicated just to clarifying the term [1]. This is problematic not only scientifically, but also socially, as “epigenetics” is now even being used in marketing; typically to push the latest health scam. Hopefully this post can shed a little light on just what epigenetics is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>